<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>Project Log</title>
 <link href="http://ecotrust.github.com/marco-portal/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://ecotrust.github.com/marco-portal"/>
 <updated>2012-07-01T23:00:59-07:00</updated>
 <id>http://ecotrust.github.com/marco-portal</id>
 <author>
   <name>Ecotrust</name>
   <email>ks-dev@ecotrust.org</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>NOAA CSC Regional Portal Workshop</title>
   <link href="http://ecotrust.github.com/marco-portal/event/2012/06/28/noaa-csc-portal-workshop"/>
   <updated>2012-06-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://ecotrust.github.com/marco-portal/event/2012/06/28/noaa-csc-portal-workshop</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This week members of the MARCO Portal development team attended a Regional Data Management and Portal Development Workshop hosted by NOAA at the NOAA Coastal Services Center in Charleston. Technical representatives from most of the regional ocean councils were there as well as folks from some of the regions of the U.S. Integrated Ocean Observing System (IOOS).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Topics centered around how these different groups overlap and should be working together whether it&amp;#8217;s sharing data, best practices, or technology. NOAA as the overarching national agency was keenly interested in the role it could play enabling collaboration between these groups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few of the key things that came out of the workshop were:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discussion on some of the features and standards that regional data portals should all have. The NOAA CMSP registry is seen as a strong model for how data can be presented thematically and what forms the data should be provided in (raw data, web services, metadata). ISO is the metadata standard of choice and CSW is the catalog standard of choice.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;ocean.data.gov is an important resource and regional data portals should find ways to work with it on some level whether its consuming national data layers, publishing regional data layers back up, or taking advantage of ocean community resources including the forums and wiki.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Need for better communication. This is the big one I think and the reason this website was created. Technical teams from each region are keenly interested in what the other regions are doing, why they chose the technology they did, best practices, hurdles along the way, and what opportunities there are for sharing technology. The problem is that everyone is busy and no one needs another meeting or phone call. Websites like these are a way for people to tune in and follow along in a distributed manner.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>New Marco Marine Planner Mapping Tool Mockups</title>
   <link href="http://ecotrust.github.com/marco-portal/event/2012/06/11/portal-mapping-tool-mockups"/>
   <updated>2012-06-11T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://ecotrust.github.com/marco-portal/event/2012/06/11/portal-mapping-tool-mockups</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;After an initial needs assessment the team has worked up some preliminary mockups for the Marco Marine Planner mapping tool. Please be aware, these are a work in progress and are not finalized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In August, the entire MARCO Portal website will be getting a facelift, but the Marine Planner application is where things are getting interesting. We&amp;#8217;re moving away from the ArcServer flex interface and using the Madrona framework developed by Ecotrust in addition to a suite of other libraries. Take a look at the &lt;a href='/technology.html'&gt;technology&lt;/a&gt; page of this website to get a better understanding of how all of these different libraries are being used and follow along on the &lt;a href='http://github.com/ecotrust/marco-portal'&gt;GitHub project page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class='row'&gt;
	&lt;div class='span10'&gt;
		&lt;div class='span3'&gt;
			&lt;div class='thumbnail'&gt;
				&lt;a href='/assets/img/portal-front-page.png'&gt;&lt;img src='/assets/img/portal-front-page.png' /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
				&lt;div class='attrib caption'&gt;MARCO Portal front page&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;div class='span3'&gt;
			&lt;div class='thumbnail'&gt;
				&lt;a href='/assets/img/mockup-data-catalog.png'&gt;&lt;img src='/assets/img/mockup-data-catalog.png' /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
				&lt;div class='attrib caption'&gt;Data Catalog mockup.  NOAA CMSP Data Registry inspired&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;div class='span3'&gt;
			&lt;div class='thumbnail'&gt;
				&lt;a href='/assets/img/mockup-data-layers.png'&gt;&lt;img src='/assets/img/mockup-data-layers.png' /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
				&lt;div class='attrib caption'&gt;Data layer panel with themes and grouping&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;		
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class='row'&gt;
	&lt;div class='span10'&gt;
		&lt;div class='span3'&gt;
			&lt;div class='thumbnail'&gt;
				&lt;a href='/assets/img/mockup-designs-scenario.png'&gt;&lt;img src='/assets/img/mockup-designs-scenario.png' /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
				&lt;div class='attrib caption'&gt;Scenario planning feature&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;		
		&lt;div class='span3'&gt;
			&lt;div class='thumbnail'&gt;
				&lt;a href='/assets/img/mockup-designs-sharing.png'&gt;&lt;img src='/assets/img/mockup-designs-sharing.png' /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
				&lt;div class='attrib caption'&gt;Sharing designs/scenarios.  Google Docs inspired&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;div class='span3'&gt;
			&lt;div class='thumbnail'&gt;
				&lt;a href='/assets/img/mockup-data-layers.png'&gt;&lt;img src='/assets/img/mockup-data-layers.png' /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
				&lt;div class='attrib caption'&gt;Data layer panel&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The MARCO Marine Planner Mapping Tool will be leveraging a lot of the functionality developed for Oregon MarineMap and the Washington Marine Planner including map bookmarks, scenario planning and tradeoff analysis. The most notable difference is that with MARCO we&amp;#8217;ll be using a 2D mapping interface and we&amp;#8217;re taking additional strides to simplify the user interface, recognizing that the audience will be diverse and may not receive one-on-one training on how to use it. Approaches to simplification include themes (fishing, shipping, wind energy, etc.) and making it easier to work with large numbers of data layers.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>